Vakas Akhtar

(516)-320-9935 | vakhtar@fordham.edu | New York, NY | Linkedin | GitHub | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Recent graduate with experience in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in commercial and residential real estate. Demonstrated skills in statistical analysis and project management that help data driven organizations achieve their goals in an efficient manner. Fluent in English, Spanish, and Urdu.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, Ruby, Redux, PostgresQL, R, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Git, Bootstrap

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Thrift Paradox (Rails, React, JavaScript (ES6), HTML5, CSS3, Recharts) Personal expense tracker that rewards users for saving money GitHub | Demo

- Implemented custom back and front end user authentication by combining Rails conventions, Active Record, and customized React-Router higher order components
- Used the Exchange Rates API to retrieve live exchange rate data for multiple currencies
- Calculated compounded interest on the user's savings account and rendered the results on a line graph
- Created a custom lottery system that rewarded users for reaching their required savings goal
- Used the Recharts library for data visualization

Community To-Do List (Rails, React, JavaScript (ES6), HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap)

GitHub | Demo

Task lister that allows users to order tasks by category and customize said categories

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side
- Custom CSS to display to-do list on the main dashboard with a date selector
- Bootstrap components to display error feedback alerts for login and sign up pages
- Built a Rails API backend to handle CRUD functionality

Animal Crossing: Vanilla JS Village (CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript(ES6))

GitHub | Demo

Random social media post generator with characters from Animal Crossing

- Implemented a custom route to randomize characters
- Retrieved data from the ACNH API and seeded it into the Rails backend
- Custom CSS styling to emulate instagram

Regression Analysis of Eviction Rates (R)

<u>GitHub</u>

Econometric analysis using public crime and census data

- Performed linear regressions in R with custom equations
- Obtained unbiased standard errors of OLS coefficients under heteroscedasticity with robust standard errors
- Utilized R Shiny and Stargazer libraries for data visualization

EXPERIENCE

Luxury Homes Group

New Hyde Park, NY 06/2017 - 05/2019

Licensed Real Estate Agent 06/2017 - 05/2019

- Performed comparative market analysis on commercial, residential, and mixed-use properties
- Spoke to clients in English, Spanish, or Urdu to expand potential client pool to new markets
- Organized clients' information using Excel to add efficiency for follow-ups
- Analyzed data from Broker's previous sales and investments to assess quality of deals

EDUCATION

Flatiron School NYC, NY

Full Stack Web Development, Software Engineering

06/2020 - 10/2020

Fordham University
Bachelor's degree in Economics

Bronx, NY 08/2016 - 05/2020